<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Geekery | NJBiddle]]></title>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/categories/geekery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T13:55:46-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://njbiddle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[NJBiddle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nick@njbiddle.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XBMC]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/xbmc/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T11:17:02-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/xbmc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After going through a number of media center front ends (<a href="http://www.boxee.tv/">Boxee</a>, <a href="http://plexapp.zendesk.com/hc/en-us">Plex</a>, etc), I&rsquo;ve stuck with <a href="http://xbmc.org/">XBMC</a>. It gives me the ability to customize the interface to my liking, run on older hardware, and play nearly anything I can throw at it.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc.png" alt="XBMC" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;m running XBMC on top of a <a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/download">Ubuntu 13</a> install on an older corei3 machine I had laying around. It can output full 1080 resolution without skipping a beat over HDMI.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc2.png" alt="XBMC Movies" /></p>

<br>


<p>XBMC comes packed with features out of the box, but once you start customizing it&rsquo;s interface you really see where XBMC pulls ahead of other media center solutions.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc3.png" alt="XBMC TV" /></p>

<br>


<p>You can even run third party plugins and applications inside of XBMC. For instance, I&rsquo;m running apps to stream <a href="">Railscasts</a> videos, Hulu, Soundcloud, etc.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc4.png" alt="XBMC rails" /></p>

<br>


<p>Although buggy on Ubuntu, you can also run console ROMS out of XBMC&rsquo;s <a href="http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/">ROM Collection Browser</a>.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc5.png" alt="XBMC Roms" /></p>

<br>


<p>Finding an interface that works for you is important as well. I&rsquo;m running the <a href="http://github.com/niamu/skin.nbox">nbox theme</a> by <a href="http://github.com/niamu">Niamu</a>, slightly customized to show me just what I need on screen, without added bloat or information.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc6.png" alt="XBMC nbox" /></p>

<br>


<br>


<p>Having trouble installing XBMC, or have questions? Shoot me a comment below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[unRAID Home NAS]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/unraid-nas/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T19:27:43-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/unraid-nas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I run an <a href="http://lime-technology.com/">unRAID</a> server at home for serving media, TimeMachine backups, managing libraries, and pretty much anything else I can throw at it. For being a small (under 500MB) slackware distro, it has huge potential.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid.png" alt="Unraid" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>One of the main reasons I chose unRAID over alternatives, was being able to run a JBOD array. If I have a spare disk laying around, whether it&rsquo;s 500GB or 2TB, I can throw it in the unRAID box. I can lose one disk in my array, and still recover data via the parity disk, so it provides the redundancy I need for non-essential data (movies, music, etc).</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid4.png" alt="Unraid Array" /></p>

<br>


<p>unRAID also runs off a USB key, which saves me a SATA port on my motherboard. I&rsquo;m running unRAID on an old Dell P4 machine I had laying around, and I&rsquo;ve never felt like I&rsquo;m running out of resources. unRAID is running a handful of media applications, and also acts as a <a href="http://plex.tv/">Plex</a> server. Highly recommended if you&rsquo;re into tinkering.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid3.png" alt="Unraid Apps" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8.1 on VirtualBox]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/windows-8-dot-1-on-virtualbox/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T14:11:32-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/windows-8-dot-1-on-virtualbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running multiple environments is critical for me both in IT and web development. I&rsquo;m currently using <a href="http://virtualbox.org">virtualbox</a> on my Mac to virtualize a windows 8.1 environment (I know, I know&hellip;). Click through for a quick walkthrough.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm4.png" alt="Win 8.1 VM" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;m using virtualbox over more popular alternatives such as VMWare Fusion and Parallels because of it&rsquo;s opensource nature and more technical community background. Windows 8.1 takes a little bit more time to configure, but it installs the same as any other VM.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm.png" alt="win 8.1 vm settings" /></p>

<br>


<ol>
<li>Create a new VM shell, be sure to select your correct distro and x86 vs x64</li>
<li>Boot to your ISO, PXE, disk, etc</li>
<li>Install like normal</li>
<li>Attempt to boot</li>
</ol>


<p>If you&rsquo;re having difficulties booting, check your storage controller and chipset config. I had trouble creating a SATA controller and booting to network (PXE boot), so I had to use an IDE virtual disk.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm2.png" alt="controller settings" /></p>

<br>


<p>Assign RAM and cpu appropriately, and select ICH9 chipset if you have issues.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm3.png" alt="chipset settings" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSX Virtual Machine]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/09/osx-virtual-machine/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-09T19:03:17-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/09/osx-virtual-machine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Using a spare machine, I&rsquo;ve successfully set up a headless OSX VM on intel-based hardware. It&rsquo;s relatively under-powered, but serves my needs as a small file server and iTunes box.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/osxvm/osxvm4.png" alt="OSX VM" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>This was accomplished by running <a href="http://vmwarelearning.com/esxi/">ESXi5.1</a> patched with <a href="http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/topic/267296-esxi-5-mac-os-x-unlocker/">Donk&rsquo;s OSX unlocker</a>. After patching, you&rsquo;ll need to upload the OSX installation .dmg and boot to ISO.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/osxvm/osxvm2.png" alt="OSX VM2" /></p>

<br>


<p>Install OSX to your assigned datastore and your VM should boot right up. Originally I did this install with osx 10.8, but have since updated to 10.9 Mavericks. For the upgrade:</p>

<ol>
<li>Snapshot the VM</li>
<li>Run the upgrade as normal</li>
<li>Reboot when prompted</li>
<li>Success!</li>
<li>Remove that snapshot</li>
</ol>


<p>Assign USB devices, more ram, cores, etc for added functionality and performance.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/osxvm/osxvm3.png" alt="OSX VM3" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools I Use: Alfred]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/09/alfred/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-09T17:59:02-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/09/alfred</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven&rsquo;t used productivity apps like <a href="http://qsapp.com/">Quicksilver</a>, <a href="http://cooperteam.net/">GnomeDO</a>, etc, you need to start.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/alfred/alfred.png" alt="Alfred" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>I rely on <a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/">Alfred</a> to get around my machine quickly and efficiently. Alfred is much more than a simple app launcher. Dig in and experience some of it&rsquo;s more advanced features for yourself!</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/alfred/alfred2.png" alt="Alfred file browser" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
