<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Geekery | NJBiddle]]></title>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/categories/geekery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T13:26:47-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://njbiddle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[NJBiddle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nick@njbiddle.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XBMC]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/xbmc/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T11:17:02-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/xbmc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After going through a number of media center front ends (<a href="http://www.boxee.tv/">Boxee</a>, <a href="http://plexapp.zendesk.com/hc/en-us">Plex</a>, etc), I&rsquo;ve stuck with <a href="http://xbmc.org/">XBMC</a>. It gives me the ability to customize the interface to my liking, run on older hardware, and play nearly anything I can throw at it.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc.png" alt="XBMC" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;m running XBMC on top of a <a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/download">Ubuntu 13</a> install on an older corei3 machine I had laying around. It can output full 1080 resolution without skipping a beat over HDMI.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc2.png" alt="XBMC Movies" /></p>

<br>


<p>XBMC comes packed with features out of the box, but once you start customizing it&rsquo;s interface you really see where XBMC pulls ahead of other media center solutions.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc3.png" alt="XBMC TV" /></p>

<br>


<p>You can even run third party plugins and applications inside of XBMC. For instance, I&rsquo;m running apps to stream <a href="">Railscasts</a> videos, Hulu, Soundcloud, etc.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc4.png" alt="XBMC rails" /></p>

<br>


<p>Although buggy on Ubuntu, you can also run console ROMS out of XBMC&rsquo;s <a href="http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/">ROM Collection Browser</a>.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc5.png" alt="XBMC Roms" /></p>

<br>


<p>Finding an interface that works for you is important as well. I&rsquo;m running the <a href="http://github.com/niamu/skin.nbox">nbox theme</a> by <a href="http://github.com/niamu">Niamu</a>, slightly customized to show me just what I need on screen, without added bloat or information.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/xbmc/xbmc6.png" alt="XBMC nbox" /></p>

<br>


<br>


<p>Having trouble installing XBMC, or have questions? Shoot me a comment below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8.1 on VirtualBox]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/windows-8-dot-1-on-virtualbox/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T14:11:32-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/windows-8-dot-1-on-virtualbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running multiple environments is critical for me both in IT and web development. I&rsquo;m currently using <a href="http://virtualbox.org">virtualbox</a> on my Mac to virtualize a windows 8.1 environment (I know, I know&hellip;). Click through for a quick walkthrough.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm4.png" alt="Win 8.1 VM" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;m using virtualbox over more popular alternatives such as VMWare Fusion and Parallels because of it&rsquo;s opensource nature and more technical community background. Windows 8.1 takes a little bit more time to configure, but it installs the same as any other VM.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm.png" alt="win 8.1 vm settings" /></p>

<br>


<ol>
<li>Create a new VM shell, be sure to select your correct distro and x86 vs x64</li>
<li>Boot to your ISO, PXE, disk, etc</li>
<li>Install like normal</li>
<li>Attempt to boot</li>
</ol>


<p>If you&rsquo;re having difficulties booting, check your storage controller and chipset config. I had trouble creating a SATA controller and booting to network (PXE boot), so I had to use an IDE virtual disk.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm2.png" alt="controller settings" /></p>

<br>


<p>Assign RAM and cpu appropriately, and select ICH9 chipset if you have issues.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/win8vm/win8vm3.png" alt="chipset settings" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
