<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Networking | NJBiddle]]></title>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/categories/networking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://njbiddle.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-25T12:37:54-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://njbiddle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[NJBiddle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nick@njbiddle.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DD-WRT VPN]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/dd-wrt-vpn/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T15:26:37-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/dd-wrt-vpn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<br>


<p>If you&rsquo;re not already using a VPN, you need to start. Securing your traffic while on public networks and creating a simple point of access to your home network can be accomplished quickly if you&rsquo;re already using <a href="http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/index">DD-WRT</a>.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/vpn/vpn4.png" alt="DD-WRT VPN" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>First, start running <a href="http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/index">DD-WRT</a> or <a href="http://www.polarcloud.com/tomato">Tomato</a> on your router at home. After you&rsquo;re up and running, configuring the VPN is easy. Head over to Services > VPN, and enter your config options as seen below:</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/vpn/vpn.png" alt="DD-WRT config" /></p>

<br>


<p>NOTE: Be sure to use correct formatting in the username/password field</p>

<p><code> username * password * </code></p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t forget to enable PPTP VPN in Security > VPN Passthrough</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/vpn/vpn2.png" alt="DD-WRT VPN passthrough" /></p>

<br>


<p>Configure the VPN client-side, and you&rsquo;ll be good to go. If you need help, drop a line below.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/vpn/vpn3.png" alt="VPN Access" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools I Use: BTSync]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/btsync/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T14:40:24-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/15/btsync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<br>


<p>Wanting to move away from Dropbox, I tried out <a href="http://www.bittorrent.com/sync/downloads">BTSync</a> as an alternative. Although not a complete replacement, it definitely has its perks.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/btsync/btsync.png" alt="BTSync" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>BTSync does have a slackware version available that <a href="http://github.com/overbyrn/UnRAID">Overbyrn</a> has compiled into a unRAID plugin <a href="http://github.com/overbyrn/UnRAID">here</a>. I run this on my box as a server, with my Mac, Nexus, and iPhone as clients to sync random files, ebooks, etc.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/btsync/btsync2.png" alt="BTSync" /></p>

<br>


<p>My main reason for using BTSync is security. BTSync uses P2P sharing to sync files only between devices with the assigned private security key. No data is moved to foreign servers.</p>

<p>Definitely more secure, but also not widely used. Sharing data with other users or clients requires them to have the BTSync client installed, so it&rsquo;s not the best option for ALL scenarios, but if you&rsquo;re looking to keep directories and files in-sync across multiple devices it fits the bill quite well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[unRAID Home NAS]]></title>
    <link href="http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/unraid-nas/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T19:27:43-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://njbiddle.com/blog/2014/02/10/unraid-nas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I run an <a href="http://lime-technology.com/">unRAID</a> server at home for serving media, TimeMachine backups, managing libraries, and pretty much anything else I can throw at it. For being a small (under 500MB) slackware distro, it has huge potential.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid.png" alt="Unraid" /></p>

<br>


<!--more-->


<p>One of the main reasons I chose unRAID over alternatives, was being able to run a JBOD array. If I have a spare disk laying around, whether it&rsquo;s 500GB or 2TB, I can throw it in the unRAID box. I can lose one disk in my array, and still recover data via the parity disk, so it provides the redundancy I need for non-essential data (movies, music, etc).</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid4.png" alt="Unraid Array" /></p>

<br>


<p>unRAID also runs off a USB key, which saves me a SATA port on my motherboard. I&rsquo;m running unRAID on an old Dell P4 machine I had laying around, and I&rsquo;ve never felt like I&rsquo;m running out of resources. unRAID is running a handful of media applications, and also acts as a <a href="http://plex.tv/">Plex</a> server. Highly recommended if you&rsquo;re into tinkering.</p>

<br>


<p><img src="/images/unraid/unraid3.png" alt="Unraid Apps" /></p>

<br>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
